<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[thomashw]]></title>
  <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-18T17:38:38-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://thomashw.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Hewton-Waters]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Exchangenge iOS Settings]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/microsoft-exchangenge-ios-settings/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-18T17:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/microsoft-exchangenge-ios-settings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My company doesn’t officially support adding a Microsoft Exchange email/calendar account to your iOS device unless you install a certain application and certificate. I didn’t want to do this since it enables them to do a lot more than just enable email on my phone.</p>

<p>We have Microsoft Exchange webmail accessible from anywhere so I eventually figured out the correct settings to use from the webmail URL to add a Microsoft Exchange account to my iOS devices that pushes my work email, address book, and calendar.</p>

<p>Once I log in, our webmail URL looks something like this: https://subdomain.domain.com/owa</p>

<p>The settings I used to add the Microsoft Exchange account to my iOS devices were:
Server: subdomain.domain.com
Domain: domain
Username: same username as logging in to webmail (no domain required)
Password: same password
Use SSL: On</p>

<p>Once I used those settings and clicked Done checkmarks appeared beside each form field and then the account was added. It took maybe 5-10 minutes before I could access my email and calendar (I got a couple error messages during that time). I think it was while emails were being downloaded.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RP-PPPoE &amp; pppd - LCP: timeout sending Config-Requests]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/rp-pppoe-and-pppd-lcp-timeout-sending-config-requests/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T19:34:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/rp-pppoe-and-pppd-lcp-timeout-sending-config-requests</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was installing RP-PPPoE 3.11 on CentOS 5.2 (Linux version 2.6). This will enable us to authenticate users connecting to our network through one of our computers (which I&#8217;ll call &#8216;server&#8217;).</p>

<p>Whenever I tried to connect to the server from a client, I would see the following in /var/log/messages on the server:</p>

<pre><code>pppd[22137]: pppd 2.4.4 started by root, uid 0
pppd[22137]: Using interface ppp0
pppd[22137]: Connect: ppp0 &lt;--&gt; /dev/pts/1
pppd[22137]: LCP: timeout sending Config-Requests 
pppd[22137]: Connection terminated.
pppd[22137]: Modem hangup
pppoe[22140]: Timeout waiting for PADO packets
pppd[22137]: Exit.
</code></pre>

<p>After doing a ton of digging, I finally read a tip to try disabling the syslog daemon. This tip didn&#8217;t include why you would need to do this or what it had to do with RP-PPPoE, but I was running out of options so I gave it a try.</p>

<pre><code>sudo /etc/init.d/syslog stop
</code></pre>

<p>I had authentiation and most other options disabled on RP-PPPoE as I was just trying to get the server and client connected, and lo-and-behold, the client connected right away! This was really weird, since what does syslog have to do with RP-PPPoE and why would it stop the connection from working?</p>

<p>I did a bunch of searching, and found the following two posts:</p>

<p><a href="http://marc.info/?l=linux-ppp&amp;m=118661751530643">pppd and rp-pppoe LCP timeout issues</a></p>

<p><a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=222295">Bug 222295 - ppp-2.4.3-6.2.1 conflict with syslog on pppoe-server.</a></p>

<p>If you look through them, you&#8217;ll see it has to do with pppd version 2.4.4, which is the version running (as can be seen in the /var/log/messages log above). You can also test which version of pppd you&#8217;re using with <code>pppd --version</code>.</p>

<p>The specific issue has to do with the placement of a <code>closelog()</code> function call in main.c. Here&#8217;s the patch that&#8217;s included in the second post:</p>

<pre><code>--- ppp-2.4.4/pppd/main.c.orig 2006-06-04 07:52:50.000000000 +0400
+++ ppp-2.4.4/pppd/main.c 2007-11-09 14:47:20.000000000 +0300
@@ -1567,6 +1567,8 @@
if (errfd == 0 || errfd == 1)
errfd = dup(errfd);

+ closelog();
+
/* dup the in, out, err fds to 0, 1, 2 */
if (infd != 0)
dup2(infd, 0);
@@ -1575,7 +1577,6 @@
if (errfd != 2)
dup2(errfd, 2);

- closelog();
if (log_to_fd &gt; 2)
close(log_to_fd);
if (the_channel-&gt;close)
</code></pre>

<p>As you can see, the patch just relocates the function call a few lines up. What I decided to do was download the latest version of pppd, ensure the patch was already applied, and install it overtop of pppd 2.4.4 already on the system. I downloaded the latest version (2.4.5) from <a href="ftp://ftp.samba.org/pub/ppp/">here</a>, inspected main.c to make sure the patch was already applied (which it was), and followed the installation instructions to install it.</p>

<p>Once I had 2.4.5 installed, I confirmed with <code>pppd --version</code>, ran the server and tried connecting with a client. I ended up needing to rebuild 2.4.5 after changing the install path in the configure script because it wasn&#8217;t installing to the same directory as 2.4.4 and RP-PPPoE was still using 2.4.4. 2.4.4 was located in /usr/sbin, while the configure script configured 2.4.5 to install to /usr/local/sbin by default. After changing the configure script to install to /usr/sbin, RP-PPPoE used the correct version and the client connected without issue! The logs in /var/log/messages now look like this:</p>

<pre><code>pppd[4075]: pppd 2.4.5 started by root, uid 0
pppd[4075]: Using interface ppp0
pppd[4075]: Connect: ppp0 &lt;--&gt; /dev/pts/1
pppd[4075]: local  IP address 10.0.0.1
pppd[4075]: remote IP address 10.67.15.1
</code></pre>

<p>After I got rid of that bug, I started turning features back on (such as authentication), and everything worked.</p>

<p>The two main tutorials I read to actually set up RP-PPPoE were:</p>

<p><a href="http://darmawan-salihun.blogspot.ca/2008/12/setting-up-basic-pppoe-server-in-linux.html">Setting-up Basic PPPoE Server in Linux (x86_64 Platform)</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.howtodoityourself.org/2010/12/01/pppoe-server-how-to-do-it-yourself.html">PPPoE Server – How To Do It Yourself</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[VirtualBox Shared Folders]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/virtualbox-shared-folders/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T10:05:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/virtualbox-shared-folders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I was trying to get shared folders working using VirtualBox. I have the host as Ubuntu 12.04 and a guest using Ubuntu 11.04. For the life of me I couldn&#8217;t get them to work. I followed the instructions on installing the Linux Guest Additions from VirtualBox&#8217;s site and set up shared folders the same way many tutorials/blogs suggested, but every time I went to mount the shared folder I would get this error:</p>

<pre><code>/sbin/mount.vboxsf: mounting failed with the error: No such Device
</code></pre>

<p>I <em>finally</em> found a post explaining that the issue was the installation of modules while installing the Guest Additions. VirtualBox&#8217;s <a href="http://www.virtualbox.org/manual/ch04.html#idp18411760">website</a> instructs to install <em>just</em> dkms before running the Guest Additions script, but this was incorrect. One indication that this is the issue is to run  <code>ls mod | grep vbox</code>. You <strong>shouldn&#8217;t</strong> see vboxsf.</p>

<p>In order to build the modules necessary for shared folders, the following three packages need to be installed before running the Guest Additions installation script:</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get install dkms build-essential linux-headers-generic      
</code></pre>

<p>After that, I re-ran the Guest Additions script by connecting the VBoxGuestAdditions.iso as a storage device (using phpvirtualbox), mounting the device at /dev/scd0, and running the script:</p>

<pre><code>sudo mount /dev/scd0 /media/cdrom
cd /media/cdrom
./VBoxLinuxAdditions.run
</code></pre>

<p>Once that had completed, I restarted and ran <code>ls mod | grep vbox</code>. You <strong>should</strong> see see vboxsf.</p>

<p>One that&#8217;s done, you should be able to mount your shared folders, like so:</p>

<pre><code>mount -t vboxsf -o uid=1000,gid=1000 d /media/sf_d
</code></pre>

<p>I put one of those commands for each of my shared folders in /etc/rc.local. Make sure you create the sf_d folder in /media before trying to mount it there, and change uid and gid to the user you want the mount to be mounted under.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/08/24/steve-jobs/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-24T23:17:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/08/24/steve-jobs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One year ago today, Steve Jobs resigned as CEO of Apple.</p>

<p>One of my favourite keynotes to watch is the original introduction of the iPhone. Right around the 29 minute mark gives me chills. You can download it on iTunes and I think you should, even if you don&#8217;t want to watch it right away. It&#8217;s an iconic event and it would be a shame to not have it if it&#8217;s ever taken off of iTunes.</p>

<p>Download it <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/ca/podcast/apple-keynotes/id275834665">here</a>.</p>

<p>His keynotes were special. I&#8217;ll miss them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview Questions]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/interview-questions/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-21T07:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/interview-questions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You should know the answer to all of these questions before going into an interview. They aren&#8217;t difficult questions, but knowing the answers beforehand will certainly reduce stress while you&#8217;re in the interview trying to come up with an answer.</p>

<ol>
<li>Why do you want to work for us?</li>
<li>How do you think you could contribute to our company?</li>
<li>What kind of work do you like best?</li>
<li>Do you work well with others?</li>
<li>What are your hobbies?</li>
<li>What would you like to do when you graduate?</li>
<li>Are you good at taking direction?</li>
<li>Are you good at giving direction?</li>
<li>Are you good at multitasking, or do you prefer to focus on one thing?</li>
<li>Do you like to be busy?</li>
<li>What would you like to learn if you worked for us?</li>
<li>What do you do in your spare time?</li>
<li>What would you do if you disagreed with your boss?</li>
<li>What would you do if you had a conflict with a co-worker?</li>
<li>Are you comfortable talking about your ideas?</li>
<li>Are you comfortable talking in front of a group?</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
