<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: running | thomashw]]></title>
  <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/categories/running/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-20T12:53:03-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://thomashw.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Hewton-Waters]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2013/04/06/running/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-06T16:56:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2013/04/06/running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a post I read on reddit. Pretty awesome so I thought I'd share.</p>

<blockquote><p>This is sort of how I started running too. When my life was falling apart and I thought nothing else could go right I started going to the gym to force myself into something social everday. Just to interact with people. Just to do SOMETHING.</p>

<p>And then I started running. And then it started being about me. And that feeling. And the act. And how free it was. How independent. How strong. How I didn't have to hold back anything like I did with the rest of the world. On the treadmill, on the trails, on the track, in my running shoes I was allowed to be raw anger and pain and frustration and loneliness and strength, too, because fuck the world that doesn't think it takes strength to be alone.</p>

<p>Fast forward six months - my first 5k. Six more - half marathon. A year - marathon. I'm still the only one I know who's done it. I'm about to start training for the triathlon. And yeah, I like my body a lot better now, not so much because of the way it looks but because it is a powerful, independent, free extension of the strength I carry and I can show that any time.</p>

<p>So you, more power to you. Run. Run for as long as it makes you happy. There's nothing like that first ten miler that you take in the middle of the night without your phone or telling anyone where you went and you think it's never going to end and when you finally finish your legs are fucked for the next three days, but fuckitall if it wasn't worth it.
Running's like that. Welcome to the family.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/ForeverAlone/comments/1bs12o/working_out/c99imx6">Original Post</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
