<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: virtualbox | thomashw]]></title>
  <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/categories/virtualbox/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-02T21:30:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://thomashw.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Hewton-Waters]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[VirtualBox Shared Folders]]></title>
    <link href="http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/virtualbox-shared-folders/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T10:05:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://thomashw.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/virtualbox-shared-folders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I was trying to get shared folders working using VirtualBox. I have the host as Ubuntu 12.04 and a guest using Ubuntu 11.04. For the life of me I couldn't get them to work. I followed the instructions on installing the Linux Guest Additions from VirtualBox's site and set up shared folders the same way many tutorials/blogs suggested, but every time I went to mount the shared folder I would get this error:</p>

<pre><code>/sbin/mount.vboxsf: mounting failed with the error: No such Device
</code></pre>

<p>I <em>finally</em> found a post explaining that the issue was the installation of modules while installing the Guest Additions. VirtualBox's <a href="http://www.virtualbox.org/manual/ch04.html#idp18411760">website</a> instructs to install <em>just</em> dkms before running the Guest Additions script, but this was incorrect. One indication that this is the issue is to run  <code>ls mod | grep vbox</code>. You <strong>shouldn't</strong> see vboxsf.</p>

<p>In order to build the modules necessary for shared folders, the following three packages need to be installed before running the Guest Additions installation script:</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get install dkms build-essential linux-headers-generic      
</code></pre>

<p>After that, I re-ran the Guest Additions script by connecting the VBoxGuestAdditions.iso as a storage device (using phpvirtualbox), mounting the device at /dev/scd0, and running the script:</p>

<pre><code>sudo mount /dev/scd0 /media/cdrom
cd /media/cdrom
./VBoxLinuxAdditions.run
</code></pre>

<p>Once that had completed, I restarted and ran <code>ls mod | grep vbox</code>. You <strong>should</strong> see see vboxsf.</p>

<p>One that's done, you should be able to mount your shared folders, like so:</p>

<pre><code>mount -t vboxsf -o uid=1000,gid=1000 d /media/sf_d
</code></pre>

<p>I put one of those commands for each of my shared folders in /etc/rc.local. Make sure you create the sf_d folder in /media before trying to mount it there, and change uid and gid to the user you want the mount to be mounted under.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
